[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
So this notion of collaborative filtering is that somehow we wanna leverage
协同过滤技术为用户做推荐的依据有
what other people have purchased.
其他所有人的历史购物记录和
And the case of product recommendation or other links more generically between
产品推荐的实例和
users and items, to make recommendations for other users.
用户和商品的一般化的关联关系
And so it seems very intuitive that when we're thinking about doing product
显然 当我们为用户推荐产品时
recommendation that we wanna build in information like
如果有人买过这件商品
if a person bought this item, then
而且可能他们大部分都买过其他某些物品
they're probably also interested in some other item because we've seen lots and
那么我们有必要将这些过去经常一起买的物品
lots of examples in the past of people buying those pairs of items together.
推荐给此时买这件商品的用户
Maybe not simultaneously, at the same time, but
当然可能这些物品不是同时购买的
in the course of their purchase histories.
但只要是在历史购物记录里就可以考虑
Okay, so this brings us to the idea of co-occurrence of purchases.
这样我们就有了同现购买的概念
So, for example, if I was just on Amazon, buying diapers, well, we've probably
举例来说就是 我们见过 很多买了尿布的人还会买婴儿湿巾
seen lots of examples of people who bought diapers also bought baby wipes.
如果我刚在Amazon买了尿布
Okay, so how can we use this type of co-occurrence of
我们怎么利用这种同现购买现象
purchases to make recommendations?
帮助我们做出推荐呢？
[SOUND] Okay [LAUGH] so let's talk about this co-occurrence
好的 我们先讲一下接下来要构建的
matrix that we're gonna build up.
同现矩阵
And this is gonna store all of our information about which purchases
这个矩阵记录着哪些商品是被
people bought together.
相同的用户购买的
And again, when I say together I don't mean simultaneously,
我必须再次申明用户不一定 是同时购买的这些商品
just together at some point in their history of purchases.
可能是一段时间内分次购买的
So I'm gonna build up this Matrix C and this matrix is an items by items matrix.
接下来我将构建一个行列都是物品的矩阵C
Okay, so we're gonna list all the different items for
首先矩阵的所有行对应
our rows of this matrix.
所有不同的物品
And likewise, all the different items, for the columns.
同样地 所有列也对应所有的物品
So, for example, maybe this row of this matrix,
比如矩阵这一行对应的是
might be the row corresponding to diapers.
尿布
And then if this is lets say the third row of this matrix,
我们假设是矩阵的第三行
then I would also have that the third column of this
那么矩阵的第三列也是
matrix Corresponds to diapers as well.
对应的尿布
Okay, and so if I want to say that many people purchased diapers and baby wipes,
那么如何描述很多人会同时买尿布和婴儿湿巾呢
let's look at the row for diapers and then we scroll over to the column for,
首先找到尿布对应的行 然后找到婴儿湿巾对应的列
let's say this column here, is for baby wipes.
比如说婴儿湿巾列在这里
And in this entry, of this matrix there's some number entered.
这样就可以定位到它们对应着的某个值
And that number represents the number of people.
这个值就代表着
Purchasing both diapers and baby wipes.
同时购买尿布和婴儿湿巾的用户数
Okay, well, let me ask you a question.
好的，再来一个问题
Is the number of people who purchased diapers and baby wipes
同时购买尿布和婴儿湿巾的用户数和
the same as the number of people who purchased baby wipes and diapers?
同时购买婴儿湿巾和尿布的用户数一样吗
Yes, so we would go to the baby wipes row.
这是当然的，所以矩阵中的
And this diapers column and
婴儿湿巾行和尿布列对应的用户数值
notice that this is the exactly same number, okay?
和之前定位的那个用户数值是一样的
And so what this means is this a symmetric matrix that,
其实这个矩阵是对称矩阵
if we look across the diagonal here, Then we're gonna see a reflection.
它是关于对角线对称的
If we took this matrix and folded it across that little diagonal line I
如果将它沿对角线折一下
just drew you would get exactly the same numbers matching up.
对应位置的数值都是对应相等的
Okay, and just to reiterate the way we're gonna build up this co-occurrence matrix,
好的，将矩阵所有位置的值 都这样填完以后就能得到同现矩阵
is we're gonna search through all the user's history of purchases they've made,
我们可以从中找到所有用户的购买记录并
and count.
做一定的计算
And every time we see a purchase of diapers we'll add
每当有一笔含有尿布的购买交易
of diapers along with all the other items, we're gonna add one to that entry,
我们就将跟它同时购买的物品对应列值加一
and we're gonna keep incrementing that matrix as we're searching over users.
我们会这样将所有用户的购买记录扫一遍 最终构建出同现矩阵的值
Okay, but now let's talk about how we're gonna use this co-occurrence matrix
接下来我们再讲一讲如何使用同现矩阵
in order to make recommendations.
做商品推荐
And it's really, really straight forward.
其实非常简单粗暴
So let's say that a user has just purchased diapers, and
假设有一个用户刚买了尿布
I wanna make some recommendation for them.
我想再推荐一些商品给他
Well what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna look at the diapers row of this matrix,
那么我将先找到同现矩阵C中的尿布行
so if we go back, to that, C matrix here,
我们可以回顾下矩阵C
I'm gonna grab out this diapers row, and I'm just gonna draw that row here.
将尿布行提出来放在这
And what this row has is how often people bought diapers and,
这行的值表示人们买了多少次尿布
remember, baby wipes was one of the items.
其中一项值表示有多少次买了尿布的同时 还买了婴儿湿巾
Oops, sorry, not baby items, baby wipes.
不好意思 听起来有点拗口
And that has, let's say a 100 counts.
假设婴儿湿巾这项值为100
And then there's also let's say pacifiers.
同时假设还有奶嘴这一项
And maybe there are 4 counts of pacifiers.
对应值为4
Let's think of something else.
再比如
So let's say that there's some DVD, let's say there's no counts of those DVDs.
还有DVD这一项 值为0
We're gonna have this whole vector of counts of how many times people
这样我们就有了整个向量的值
who bought diapers, bought all these other products.
每一位值代表着买了尿布的人 同时还买了某些商品的次数
Using this,
这样的话
now we can very straightforwardly make our recommendations.
我们就可以很简单地做出推荐了
All we do is we sort this vector and
我们只要将向量中的值降序排序
recommend the items with the largest counts.
然后推荐值很大的那些商品
So maybe, we'll recommend baby wipes, and milk, and baby food, and
我们可能会给刚买了尿布的用户推荐婴儿湿巾
things like this for somebody who just purchased diapers.
牛奶 婴儿食品之类的商品
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community